<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Minnesota Department of Transportation</origin><title>Scenic Byways in Minnesota</title><pubinfo><publish>Minnesota Department of Transportation</publish></pubinfo><onlink>ftp://ftp.gisdata.mn.gov/pub/gdrs/data/pub/us_mn_state_dot/trans_roads_mndot_tis/metadata/metadata.html</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>Scenic byway represents road centerlines for all public roads within the State of Minnesota which are designated as scenic byways in a state statute. The roads are attributed with information based on their designated route. 

**MnDOT LRS data files will come in two versions, one ending in non-measured which does not contain calibrations.  These files are good for reference material.  The other version without the non-measured has calibrations and can be used to run linear events or extract measures.  These versions require contacting MnDOT to obtain.  The calibrations in them are not compatible with older Transportation Information System/GIS BaseMap measures. **
</abstract><supplinf>State of MN</supplinf><purpose>Scenic byway was developed to fill a need at MnDOT for a continuous, statewide GIS base map of the Scenic Byways of the State. </purpose></descript><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><accconst>None.</accconst><useconst>By accepting this data, the user agrees not to transmit this data or provide access to it or any part of it to another party or the public unless the user shall include with the data a copy of the disclaimer. The disclaimer can be found in Section 6 of this document (Distribution Liability). </useconst><timeperd><current>Data is complete through end of construction for date referenced. Construction subsequent to said date is in process to being entered and may or may not be included.
			</current></timeperd><spdom><bounding><westbc>-97.508970</westbc><eastbc>-89.028990</eastbc><northbc>49.652543</northbc><southbc>43.192405</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekey>Linear Referencing System, LRS, Scenic, Byway, Tourism, Route, and Road </themekey><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt></theme><place><placekey>Minnesota </placekey></place></keywords><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Transportation</cntorg><cntper>Peter Morey</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Systems and Coordination Section Director</cntpos><cntaddr><address>395 John Ireland Blvd.</address><city>Saint Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55155</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-366-3872</cntvoice><cntfax>651-366-3886</cntfax><cntemail>linearreferencingsystem.admin.dot@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><metainfo><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>ftp://ftp.gisdata.mn.gov/pub/gdrs/data/pub/us_mn_state_dot/trans_roads_mndot_tis/metadata/metadata.html</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Transportation</cntorg><cntper>Kyle House</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Research Analyst Intermediate</cntpos><cntaddr><address>395 John Ireland Blvd.</address><city>Saint Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55155</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-366-3873</cntvoice><cntfax>651-366-3886</cntfax><cntemail>linearreferencingsystem.admin.dot@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><distinfo><distliab>The State of Minnesota makes no representations or warranties expressed or implied, with respect to the reuse of the data provided herewith regardless of its format or the means of its transmission. There is no guarantee or representation to the user as to the accuracy, currency, suitability, or reliability of this data for any purpose. The user accepts the data as is. The State of Minnesota assumes no responsibility for loss or damage incurred as a result of any user's reliance on this data. All maps and other material provided herein are protected by copyright. Permission is granted to copy and use the materials herein.</distliab><stdorder><ordering>The data may be requested from the Contact person listed in the metadata.</ordering></stdorder><resdesc>Scenic Byway NM</resdesc><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Transportation</cntorg><cntper>Peter Morey</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Systems and Coordination Section Director</cntpos><cntaddr><address>395 John Ireland Blvd.</address><city>Saint Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55155</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-366-3872</cntvoice><cntfax>651-366-3886</cntfax><cntemail>linearreferencingsystem.admin.dot@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><dataqual><lineage><procstep><procdesc>Originally coded in the legacy Transportation Information System (TIS) and migrated into the new Linear Referencing System (LRS). Data created from local authority notes, review of online data sources, construction plans and video log.</procdesc></procstep></lineage><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Location accuracy for features derived from USGS 7.5-minute quadrangles cannot be assumed to exceed National Map Accuracy Standards for 1:24,000 scale maps (+/- 40 feet or 12 meters). Accuracy of updates based on imagery is dependent on the resolution of the imagery used. Imagery used for updates would represent the best imagery available at the time of the update.
				</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>N/A</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc></dataqual><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>Scenic Byway NM</enttypl></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>SCENIC_BYWAY_CODE</attrlabl></attr><attr><attrlabl>OBJECT_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>Unique ID for each record</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>ROUTE_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>The Route ID for the LRS will be a unique ID for a route within a jurisdiction. This field is filled in with the following data entry mask: SSGGGGGGGGGGNNNNAD. The SS portion is a 2- character code indicating the jurisdiction of the ownership of the route (Ex. '01' = Interstate, '02' = U.S. Highway, '07' = County Road). The GGGGGGGGGG portion is the Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) ID for the jurisdiction of the route in the case of a trunk highway route it will be all zeros. The NNNN portion is for the actual designated route number. The A portion is an alpha for all routes; for routes such as I35E it will contain the letter at the end of the route 'number', and for all other routes it will be the dash character “-“. The D portion indicates whether the routes direction of travel is 'I'ncreasing with mileage or 'D'ecreasing.</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl>DESCRIPTION</attrlabl></attr></detailed></eainfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>