<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Minnesota Department of Transportation</origin><title>Water Navigation Information in Minnesota</title><pubinfo><publish>Minnesota Department of Transportation</publish></pubinfo><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/trans-water-navigations</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>The physical location of Locks and Dams maintained by the US Army Corp of Engineers along Navigable Waterways (Mississippi River) in the State of Minnesota.

Navigable water, Minnesota represents Navigable waterway centerlines for all navigable waterways within the state of Minnesota. It originated as an arc coverage with the U. S. Army Corps of Engineers. Then MnDOT extracted the arcs that lay within the state boundary. A description of the Navigable water layer is included in Section 5 of this document - Entity and Attribute Overview.

Check other metadata records in this package for more information on Locks, Dams, and navigable water
</abstract><purpose>To create a spatial representation for mapping the location for Locks and Dams in the State of Minnesota. 

NAVIGABLE WATER, MINNESOTA was developed to fill a need at Minnesota Department of Transportation for a GIS layer of navigable waterways within the state for planning purposes.
</purpose><supplinf>State of Minnesota</supplinf></descript><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-97.508970</westbc><eastbc>-89.028990</eastbc><northbc>49.652543</northbc><southbc>43.192405</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><place><placekey>Minnesota</placekey></place><theme><themekey>transportation, inland, Waters, navigation, navigable water, River, Routes</themekey><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt></theme></keywords><accconst>None.</accconst><useconst>None. Please check sources, scale, accuracy, currentness and other available information. Please confirm that you are using the most recent copy of both data and metadata.  Acknowledgement of the publisher would be appreciated.</useconst><timeperd><current>Data is published weekly to the GeoCommons, but maybe maintained on a different cycle.  Open package to review specific layer for more detail.</current></timeperd><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Transportation</cntorg><cntper>Peter Morey</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Systems and Coordination Section Director</cntpos><cntaddr><address>395 John Ireland Blvd.</address><city>Saint Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55155</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-366-3872</cntvoice><cntfax>651-366-3886</cntfax><cntemail>linearreferencingsystem.admin.dot@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><distinfo><distliab>The State of Minnesota makes no representations or warranties expressed or implied, with respect to the reuse of the data provided herewith regardless of its format or the means of its transmission. There is no guarantee or representation to the user as to the accuracy, currency, suitability, or reliability of this data for any purpose. The user accepts the data as is. The State of Minnesota assumes no responsibility for loss or damage incurred as a result of any user's reliance on this data. All maps and other material provided herein are protected by copyright. Permission is granted to copy and use the materials herein.</distliab><stdorder><ordering>The data may be requested from the Contact person listed in the Distribution Contact.</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Transportation</cntorg><cntper>Peter Morey</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Data Systems and Coordination Section Director</cntpos><cntaddr><address>395 John Ireland Blvd.</address><city>Saint Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55155</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-366-3872</cntvoice><cntfax>651-366-3886</cntfax><cntemail>linearreferencingsystem.admin.dot@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Transportation</cntorg><cntper>Kyle House</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Research Analyst Intermediate</cntpos><cntaddr><address>395 John Ireland Blvd.</address><city>Saint Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55155</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-366-3873</cntvoice><cntfax>651-366-3886</cntfax><cntemail>linearreferencingsystem.admin.dot@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>